Noel Phyllis Birkby Papers, 1932-1994
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES III. ARCHITECTURE (1962-1993, n.d.), 9 linear ft.
  This series consists of materials related to Birkby's work as an architect and architectural consultant, and to architecture in general. It is arranged in three subseries: General, Projects, and Subject Files.
  Materials filed in the General subseries pertain to Birkby's employment and certification as an architect and architectural consultant. Included are correspondence, bids, applications, minutes, and reports.
  The Projects subseries, consists of materials related to architectural projects for which Birkby played a design role. Included are, bids, evaluations, drawings, specifications, contracts, notes, and miscellaneous materials. Standard-sized materials are arranged alphabetically by name of client or, where applicable, by name of project. Oversize materials are stored separately in flat files. They are arranged alphabetically by name of client or, where applicable, by the name of the project.
  Materials in the Subject Files, consist of clippings, articles, booklets, pamphlets related to architecture. They are arranged alphabetically by subject.
- SERIES IV. RESEARCH, SPEAKING, AND WRITING (1970-1990, n.d.), 4.75 linear ft.
  This series consists of notes, drafts, manuscripts, published articles and books, subject files, research materials, publicity materials, and clippings related to Birkby's research, writing projects, lectures, and workshops. The series is arranged in two subseries: General and Women and the Built Environment. General material is arranged alphabetically by title of work (if any) or by topic (when untitled). The Women and the Built Environment subseries is divided into nine sections reflecting the various materials produced or collected as a part of this project: Published Writings; Lectures, Conferences, and Workshops; Research Project; Curriculum Proposals; Fantasy Drawings; Book Proposals; Women's Vernacular Architecture and Buildings for Women; Grant Proposals; and Subject Files.
- SERIES V. TEACHING (1972-1992, n.d.), 2 linear ft.
  This series consists of correspondence, applications, minutes, notes, curricular materials, copies of student work, and reference and miscellaneous materials related to Birkby's work as a teacher. General materials and applications for employment are filed at the beginning of the series. They are followed by materials related to work at specific institutions which are filed alphabetically by the name of institution.
- SERIES VI. SUBJECT FILES (1960-1994, n.d.), 4.75 linear ft.
  This series consists of clippings, memorabilia, pamphlets, position papers, manuscripts, posters, publicity materials, etc., about individual women, women's issues, and homosexuality. It is divided into three subseries: Individuals (filed alphabetically by name), Women, and Homosexuality, each arranged alphabetically by subject.
- SERIES VII. PHOTOGRAPHS (1933-1994, n.d.), 7.75 linear ft.
  This series is divided into three subseries by format: Photographic prints, Negatives, and Slides and Transparencies. Photographic prints and Slides and Transparencies are divided into the following categories: Personal; Artistic Photography; Architecture; Miscellaneous; Political; Research, Speaking, and Writing; Teaching; and Travel. Negatives are numbered and arranged consecutively.
  Personal includes photographs of Birkby, her family, friends, homes, and pets. Artistic Photography reflects Birkby's use of photography as a medium of artistic expression and consists of photographs of cityscapes, scenery, flowers, etc. Architecture consists of photographs of buildings taken for study or to document projects designed by Birkby. Political consists of photographs of political actions, primarily marches and demonstrations. Research, Speaking, and Writing consists of photographs taken to illustrate research on elderly housing and women and the built environment. Teaching consists of photographs used in teaching and of projects done by Birkby's students. Travel consists of photographs taken to document the sights seen on a variety of trips.
  Negatives have not survived for every print in the Papers. Where applicable, negative numbers are noted on the reverse side of the corresponding photographic prints.
- SERIES VIII. FILMS AND VIDEOTAPES (1960-1994, n.d.), 15 linear ft.
  This series is divided into three subseries by type of material: Written material, Films, and Videotapes. Written material is filed alphabetically by the name of the film project. Films are divided into sections as follows: Architecture, Art Films, Personal, Political and Travel. Architecture consists of films taken to document the built environment. Some are documentation of projects Birkby designed, others are buildings or spaces Birkby visited. The Art Films demonstrate Birkby's use of film as a means of artistic expression. Personal consists of "home movies" of friends and family. Political consists of documentary footage of political actions. Travel is made up of films taken on a variety of trips. Within each section films are filed alphabetically by title, or if they were untitled, by subject. Titles that were written by Birkby on the film or the box in which the film was stored are listed in quotation marks.
  Videotapes are divided into two sections: Original videotapes, filed chronologically, followed by videotape Film Transfers of selected films by Birkby produced for the Sophia Smith Collection in 1997. [see Appendix for descriptive list of films].
  Original films and videotapes are closed to research. In some cases, Use copies have been made from the originals. These are marked with an asterisk [*]. Researchers interested in viewing films or videotapes for which there is no use copy should contact the Sophia Smith Collection to discuss options.
- SERIES IX. TAPE RECORDINGS (1970-1987, n.d.), 3.25 linear ft.
  Tape recordings are divided into two subseries by format: Cassettes and Reel-to-reel. Within the subseries, tapes are arranged in sections as follows: Personal; Political; Architecture; Films; Research, Speaking, and Writing; and Teaching.
  Personal tapes include audio letters, consciousness raising group sessions, therapy sessions, a psychic reading, and performances by some of Birkby's friends. They are arranged alphabetically by subject or title.
  Political recordings document marches, demonstrations, rallies, speeches, conference presentations, and interviews. They are arranged chronologically with the undated tapes filed at the end of the section.
  Architecture tapes consist primarily of speeches by others. Films consists of soundtracks, research interviews, and unedited sound recordings made for use with film footage.
  Research, Speaking, and Writing contains four tapes related to Birkby's research on housing for the elderly along with extensive recordings made as part of the project on Women and the Built Environment. The elderly housing tapes consist of meetings and discussions about this subject. The Women and the Built Environment tapes are divided into sections: Environmental Fantasy Discussions (free-ranging interview sessions with small groups of women); Lectures, Workshops, and Conference Presentations (recordings of presentations by Birkby, sometimes in collaboration with Leslie Kanes Weisman); Women's Vernacular Architecture (interviews with women about structures they had built); and Reference (mainly lectures by colleagues on this topic).
  Teaching consists of recordings of Birkby's classes at various institutions.
  Original tape recordings are closed to research. In some cases, Use copies have been made from the originals. These are marked with an asterisk [*]. Researchers interested in access to tape recordings for which there is no use copy should contact the Sophia Smith Collection to discuss options.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL AND FINANCIAL MATERIAL
  - General and clippings, 1963-82, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Address books, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Art by NPB and friends, 1953-94, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Birth certificate, diploma, will, 1932, 1950, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cancer/death: notes, 1991, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Curriculum vitae
    - c. 1966-91 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
    - Drafts, c. 1972-92 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Education
    - Class notes and papers (unidentified), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Class notes, philosophy, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Women's College of the University of North Carolina
      - General, 1950-54 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Coraddi (literary magazine), 1953-54, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Cooper Union
      - General, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Architecture 32b: class notes, 1959-60 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Course work: International University in New York project (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Yale University
      - General, 1963-83 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - First Year Design: problems, 1962-63 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Second Year Design: problems, 1963-64 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Third Year Design: problems, work, 1964-65 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Thesis project, Hofstra University Physical Education Complex, 1965, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Class work, miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Hofstra University Library Complex, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Financial
    - 51 Market Street Landmark Corporation, 1970-92, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Income tax forms, 1985-92 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980-90, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Social Security and disability, 1992-93 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Identification cards, 1980-84, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Parties, 1992, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Memorial party, 5 Jun 1994 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous, 1954-89 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Stationery, business cards, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Portfolio
    - Professional and students' work, c. 1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Professional work, c. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Students' work, c. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Sketchbooks/scrapbooks
    - "The Collected Crap of NPB," college scrapbook, 1951-c. 1954 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Items removed from "The Collected Crap of NPB," 1951-c. 1954 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - 1963-74 (Box 3, Folder 38-42)
    - c. 1975-83 (Box 4, Folder 43-52)
    - 1985-c.1992 (Box 5, Folder 53-62)
    - n.d. (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Miscellaneous sketches and notes, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 64-65)
  - Travel
    - Passports, visas, miscellaneous, 1950-85 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Mexico, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Vietnam, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 68)
      [see also SERIES IV. ARCHITECTURE, Projects, Thu Duc University]
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Individuals
    - Sidney Abbott and Barbara Love, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Florence Adams, 1978-79 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Nancy A. Allen, 1979, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Anonymous, 1955, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Tommye Barker, n.d. [1954?] (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Ellen Perry Berkeley, 1968-89 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Birkby family, miscellaneous, 1985-93, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Alice Green and Harold S. Birkby, 1955-85, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Donald Birkby, 1973-79, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Nell Blaine, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Rita Mae Brown, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Lena Ch'en, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Linda Clark and Joan Casamo, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - Nancy Colin, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Frances Doughty, 1971-74, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Ena Dubnoff (outgoing correspondence only), c. 1978 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Jan Marie DuBois, 1982, 1983, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - Louise Fishman, 1969, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - Barbara Hammer (outgoing correspondence only), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - Bertha Harris, 1972-73, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 88)
    - Jill Johnston and Ingrid Nyeboe, 1980-93, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - Rakhel Kafri, 1970-81, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 90)
    - Nina Kassen, 1974-77, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 91)
    - Margrit Kennedy, 1979-80, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 92)
    - Liz Marra, 1973, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - Millie Messick, 1955, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - Kate Millett, 1975-90, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 95)
    - Susan Mogul, 1976, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 96)
    - Kay Neelands, 1955, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 97)
    - Shannon-Joan O'Brien, 1983-90, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 98)
    - Jane O'Wyatt, 1975-94, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 99)
    - Lorinda Roland, 1967-90, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 100)
    - Renne/Gertrud Romkens, 1982-85, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - Susanne Szabo Rostock, 1976-83, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - Charlotte Rude, 1980-89, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 103)
    - [Claudia?] Samson, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Inga-Lisa Sangregorio, 1984, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Onny B. Smith, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - Students, 1977, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - Beverly Taylor, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 108)
    - Ulla Terlinden, 1981, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - Mary Vogel, 1980, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - Alida Walsh and Maria ?, 1969-78, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 111)
    - Alberta Ming-Chi Wang, 1965-67, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 112)
    - Leslie Kanes Weisman (outgoing correspondence only), 1974, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 113)
    - Mary Beth Welch, 1981, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - Charleen Whisnant and Red Clay Publishers, 1979-80, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 115)
    - Ann Witten, 1983-84, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 116)
    - Women's College of the University of North Carolina friends, 1953-58, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 117)
  - General
    - 1950-94 (Box 8, Folder 119-122)
    - Undated, A-Z (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - Fragments (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - Undated, first name only (Box 8, Folder 125)
- SERIES III. ARCHITECTURE
  - General
    - 1972-92 (Box 9, Folder 126)
    - Computer Aided Drafting/Design (CADD), 1986-88, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 127)
    - Licenses, 1968-93, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 128)
    - Office, 1985-91, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 129)
    - Job applications, bids, proposals
      - General, 1975-93, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 130-132)
      - St. Vincent's N. Richmond Alcohol Halfway House, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 133)
    - Davis Brody and Associates, 1982, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 134)
    - Dober, Paddock, Upton and Associates, 1974, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 135)
    - Gruzen and Partners, 1973-81, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 136)
    - New York City School Construction Authority prequalification questionnaire, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 137)
    - New York City Minority and Women-Owned Business Enterprises certification, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 138)
    - New York State Facilities Development Corporation
      - General, 1987-90 (Box 9, Folder 139)
      - Standard form, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 140)
      - Feasibility Studies
        - Community Residence
          - 1468 Jessup Ave., Bronx, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 141)
          - 2886/92 Valentine Ave., Bronx, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 142)
          - Evergreen and Townline Rd., Hauppauge, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 143)
          - 670 Townline Rd., Hauppauge, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 144)
        - AIDS home unit, 80 Hanson Place, Brooklyn, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 145)
    - New York State Department of Social Services Homeless Housing and Assistance Program: technical assistance contract, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 146)
    - New York State Minority and Women-Owned Business Enterprises certification, 1988-91 (Box 10, Folder 147)
    - Two Bridges Neighborhood Council, 1968-72, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 148-149)
    - United Nations School, Queens: field study, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 150)
    - United States Office of Personnel Management: application for federal employment, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 151)
    - United States Office of Management and Budget: standard form 254, 255, 1990, 1992, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 152)
    - Urban Homesteading Assistance Board, 1989, 1992, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 153)
  - Projects
    - Amethyst House, Bayley-Seton Hospital Halfway House for Women, 75 Vanderbilt Ave., Staten Island, NY, FDC # 3465
      - General, 1989-91, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 154)
      - Contracts, 1987, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 155)
      - Photocopies of photographs, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 156)
      - Clippings, 1990-91 (Box 10, Folder 157)
      - Division of Alcoholism and Alcohol Abuse regulations, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 158)
      - Elevations, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 159)
      - Consultant Evaluation, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 160)
      - Feasibility Study, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 161)
      - Correspondence, 1987-89 (Box 10, Folder 162-164)
      - Correspondence, 1990-91 (Box 11, Folder 165)
      - Job meeting minutes, 1988-90 (Box 11, Folder 166)
      - Job meeting notes, 1987-89 (Box 11, Folder 167)
      - Specifications
        - General, c. 1989 (Box 11, Folder 168)
        - Electrical, heating, mechanical, plumbing, c. 1989 (Box 11, Folder 169-172)
      - Miscellaneous drawings, 1989, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 173)
    - Arledge, 1842 Rosevilla Ave., Pasadena, CA, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 174)
    - Barber, Brooklyn, NY, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 175)
    - Bellevue Environs study, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 176)
    - Bellomo, 7455 Soundview Ave., Southold, NY, 1985-87, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 177)
    - Bronx Children's Psychiatric Center, Adolescent Day Treatment Center, 1180 Rev. James Polite Blvd., Bronx, NY, FDC # 3166
      - Correspondence and minutes, 1986-87, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 178)
      - Design Consultant Agreement, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 179)
      - Feasibility Study, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 180)
      - Miscellaneous, 1986, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 181)
    - Bronx Psychiatric Center, Community Residence, 2747 University Ave., Bronx, NY, FDC # 4722
      - Correspondence and notes, 1988-90 (Box 11, Folder 182-183)
      - Consultant evaluation, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 184)
      - Drawings, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 185)
      - Schematic Submission Report, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 186)
      - Specifications, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 187)
      - Design Consultant Agreement, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 188)
    - Cambell, Greenwood Lake, Orange County, NY, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 189)
    - Cardamon Lane Condominiums, Little Ferry, NJ, 1983-84 (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - DeSalvo, 138 West 120th St., New York, NY, 1984-85
      - General, 1989, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 191)
      - Specifications, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 192)
    - Dominguez, 424 Dahill Rd., Brooklyn, NY, 1984-85 (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - Fifth Street Women's Building, 330 East 5th St., New York, NY, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - Fox/Whitby, 3 Sheridan Sq., New York, NY: kitchen renovation, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 195)
    - Fox/Whitby, 3 Sheridan Sq., New York, NY: terrace enclosure and Springy Banks Rd., E. Hampton, NY: kitchen renovation, 1986-87 (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - Grand Central Subway Station, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 197)
    - Hayden/Maris, 8318 Riopath, [?], CA, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 198)
    - International Women's Tribune Center, 777 United Nations Plaza, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 199)
    - Jacobs, 51 8th Ave., Sea Cliff, NY, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 200)
    - Johnson, 231 East 77th St., New York, NY, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 201)
    - Johnston, Cutchogue, Southold, NY, 1985-89 (Box 12, Folder 202)
    - Knowlton, River Rd., Point Pleasant, PA, 1988-89 (Box 12, Folder 203)
    - Krogius, Lopers Path, Southampton, NY, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 204)
    - Leeds, Sagaponack, NY, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 205)
    - Lobel, Hedges Bank Drive, E. Hampton, NY
      - General, 1976-77, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 206)
      - Correspondence, notes, specifications, 1974-77, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 207)
    - Long Island University, Brooklyn Campus, Master Plan, 1966-68 (Box 13, Folder 208)
    - Long Island University, Brooklyn Campus, Library/Learning Center, 1966-70 (Box 13, Folder 209)
    - Maple Knoll Village, Springdale, OH, 1978-81 (Box 13, Folder 210)
    - New American House: competition submission, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 211)
    - Pilgrim Psychiatric Center: accessibility retrofit for various buildings
      - Specifications, general, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 212)
      - Specifications, electrical and heating, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 213)
    - Pilgrim Psychiatric Center, Community Residence, 201 Garden Place, W. Hempstead, NY, FDC #4846
      - Correspondence and notes, 1989-91, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 214)
      - Feasibility Study, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 215)
      - Design Consultant Agreement, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 216)
      - Specifications, general, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 217)
      - Specifications, electrical, plumbing, heating, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 218)
      - Job meeting minutes, 1990, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 219)
      - Consultant evaluation, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 220)
      - Schematic Submission Report, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 221)
      - Drawings, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 222)
    - Pilgrim Psychiatric Center, Community Residence, 3531 Oceanside Rd., Oceanside, NY, FDC #4845
      - Consultant evaluation, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 223)
      - Physical completion reports, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 224)
      - Job meeting minutes, 1991-92 (Box 14, Folder 225)
      - Correspondence and notes
        - 1989-Jul 1990 (Box 14, Folder 226-227)
        - Aug 1990-1992, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 228-230)
      - Contractors' applications for payment, 1991-92 (Box 14, Folder 231)
      - Consultant applications for payment, 1991-92 (Box 14, Folder 232)
      - Contract Cost Breakdowns, 1990-91 (Box 14, Folder 233)
      - Notes, misc., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 234)
      - Contractors' Progress Schedule, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 235)
      - Consultant Code Compliance Certification, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 236)
      - Outline specification, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 237)
      - Specifications, general, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 238)
      - Specifications, electrical, heating, plumbing, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 239)
      - Design Consultant Agreement, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 240)
      - Feasibility Study, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 241)
      - Schematic Submission Report, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 242)
      - Change orders, 1991-92 (Box 15, Folder 243)
      - Sample submissions, 1991-92 (Box 15, Folder 244-245)
      - Record of sample submissions and shop drawings, 1990-91 (Box 15, Folder 246)
    - Pollon, 59 East 4th St., 1985, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 247)
    - Rodriguez, 235 and 195 Bergen St., Brooklyn, NY, 1985, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 248)
    - St. Ann's School, Pierrepont St., Brooklyn, NY, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 249)
    - Sokolow, Winding Rd., Ardsley, NY, 1986, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 250)
    - Spyer, 2 Fifth Ave., New York, NY, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 251)
    - Spyer, 254 Tuckahoe Lane, So. Hampton, NY, 1986-87 (Box 15, Folder 252)
    - Thu Duc Polytechnic University, Bien Hoa, Vietnam, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 253)
    - Urban Homesteading Assistance Board, Single Room Occupancy residence, 334-336 Bergen St., Brooklyn, NY, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 254)
    - Vaughan, 201 West 138th St., New York, NY, 1985-87 (Box 16, Folder 255)
    - Vinson, 2 34th St., Stonybrook, NY, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 256)
    - Wallace, 1058-1068 Pacific St., Brooklyn, NY, 1990-91 (Box 16, Folder 257)
    - Watering Place Resort Hotel, Roatan, Honduras
      - General, 1984-85 (Box 16, Folder 258)
      - Drawings, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 259)
      - Background information, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 260)
    - Waterside Houses, east midtown Manhattan, NY, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 261)
    - Witten, Barter's Island, Boothbay, ME, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 262)
    - Women's Liberation Center, 243 West 20th St., New York, NY, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 263)
    - Women's Hall of Fame/Women's Rights National Historical Park, Seneca Falls, NY: competition submission, 1975-87 (Box 16, Folder 264)
  - Projects, OVERSIZE
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Amethyst House, Bayley-Seton Hospital Halfway House for Women, 75 Vanderbilt Ave., Staten Island, NY, FDC #3465: details, elevations, plans, sketches, 1987-91 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Arledge, 1842 Rosevilla Ave, Pasadena, CA: elevations, plans, sketches, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)